

SUBHADEEP SEN DATA ENTHUSIAST

EVERBODY LOVES A NICE STORY. I TELL MINE WITH DATA!!

CONTACT INFO

- (+91)-908-353-1573
- subhadeep.sen@outlook.in
- <u>www.linkedin.com/me</u>
- Kolkata, West Bengal, India

EDUCATION

2012-2016

Bachelor of Technology

Heritage Institute Of Technology, Kolkata

2005-2012

Secondary and Higher Secondary

Ramakrishna Mission Vidyapith, Purulia

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- PySpark
- Python
- Amazon Redshift
- O Databricks
- O AWS Athena, AWS Glue, EC2
- AWS Lambda, KMS
- AWS Networking
- Docker, Kubernetes
- O SQL
- Git-Hub
- Googling

PERSONAL DETAILS

- Sex: Male
- Nationality: Indian
- Designation : IT Analyst
- **7** Passport : Z3563344

ABOUT ME

I am a Data enthusiast looking forward to work in a stimulating environment, where I can implement and enhance my skills and knowledge to meet both organizational and individual goals. Team player with strong desires to face new challenges and expand my skills set.

EXPERIENCE

JAN 2021 - PRESENT

DATA ENGINEER

Worked as Data Engineer for migrating existing Microsoft SQL Server database and its dependencies to a centralized repository in AWS. Debugged the existing SSIS packages and re-engineered the code in Pyspark. Developed Spark applications using Pyspark, Spark-SQL for data extraction, for analysizing and transforming data to uncover insights into product analytics and customer usage patterns. Developed Glue Crawler and Jobs for loading the data to corresponding tables in Athena for downstream systems. Experience in creating docker file, building docker images and deploying the ETLs using Kubernetes. Responsible for estimating the cluster size, monitoring and troubleshooting of the spark databricks cluster.

DEC 2019 - DEC 2020 **LEAD PYTHON DEVELOPER**

Worked as Python and AWS expert for developing customized python framework to automate back-end data preparation for BI Dashboard. Developed User-Defined functions (UDF) and scripts to interact with AWS s3,uploading data to s3 bucket, unloading data from AWS s3 to Amazon Redshift tables. Developed validation and syncing scripts to auto-sync updated data to BI dashboard and refresh.

DEC 2018 - NOV 2019

LEAD BACK-END DEVELOPER & ANALYST

Worked as Amazon Redshift expert to design advanced Redshift Tables, developed optimized queries to manage large volume of data and generate back-end data for Analytical Reports of BI dashboard hosted in ec2 instance.

APR 2017 - NOV 2018 SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

Member of the development Team for developing a Data Ware House for Client using SQL

PROFESSIONAL SYNOPSIS

Overall 5+ years of IT experience with more than 1.5 years of experience as Data Engineer. Proficient in Analyzing User requirement and functional specifications. Well versed in Exploratory Data Analysis, developing Data pipeline and providing data solutions. Proficient in working with multiple AWS Cloud technologies. Team Player with excellent communication skills.



BIG-DATA

Understanding of Spark framework, big data architectures and developing Data Pipeline.

Strong Experience in data engineering and building ETL pipelines on batch and streaming data using Pyspark, SparkSQL.

Working Experience with large volume of datasets

Good working exposure on Cloud technolgies of AWS - S3, EC2, Lambda, Glue, Athena.



PYTHON

Experienced with core Python programming, developing customized scripts for automation, developing UDF (user-defined functions), ORMs(Object-Relational Mappers)

Used Python to develop customized framework to interact with AWS s3, Amazon Redshift for preparation of data on cloud. Experience in Python libraries - Numpy, Pandas, boto3.



AMAZON REDSHIFT

Understanding of Amazon Redshift Architecture and hands on experience in developing advanced Tables and optimizing complex Queries in Amazon Redshift

Used materialized view and optimizing techniques of Redshift for dealing with large volume of data and faster report loading



GIT-HUB

Used various version control tools like GitHub. Have wide experience to work with multi member working on same module.